<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kubernetes on datastrophic</title>
    <link>https://datastrophic.io/tags/kubernetes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kubernetes on datastrophic</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© 2025 datastrophic</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://datastrophic.io/tags/kubernetes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>KEMU: A Declarative Approach to Emulating Kubernetes Clusters at Scale</title>
      <link>https://datastrophic.io/declarative-kubernetes-cluster-emulation-with-kemu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://datastrophic.io/declarative-kubernetes-cluster-emulation-with-kemu/</guid>
      <description>Optimizing AI workload scheduling requires extensive experimentation and observation, but testing scheduler modifications in production is risky - configuration errors can cause multi-day delays and wasted capacity. This post introduces KEMU, a declarative Kubernetes Emulator Utility that replaces fragmented multi-tool cluster setups with a single configuration specification, enabling safe experimentation with large-scale GPU clusters on minimal resources.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secure Kubeflow Ingress and Authentication with Istio External Auth, Dex, and OAuth2 Proxy</title>
      <link>https://datastrophic.io/secure-kubeflow-ingress-and-authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://datastrophic.io/secure-kubeflow-ingress-and-authentication/</guid>
      <description>Publicly exposed insecure service endpoints on Kubernetes produce a major risk of malicious workloads being deployed on your clusters. We’ve seen reports of the Kubernetes Dashboard, the Kubeflow Central Dashboard, and the Kubeflow Pipelines all were compromised when publicly exposed to the Internet. Combined with wide RBAC permissions, a publicly exposed software with workload scheduling capabilities opens your clusters for malicious deployments to anybody knowing the endpoint URL. This blog post focuses on building a secure ingress and authentication stack on Kubernetes with Istio targeting Kubeflow installations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ultimate Kubernetes Homelab Guide: From Zero to Production Cluster On-Premises</title>
      <link>https://datastrophic.io/kubernetes-homelab-with-proxmox-kubeadm-calico-openebs-and-metallb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://datastrophic.io/kubernetes-homelab-with-proxmox-kubeadm-calico-openebs-and-metallb/</guid>
      <description>Whether you’re looking for a more powerful development environment or a production-grade Kubernetes cluster for experiments, this guide provides end-to-end deployment and configuration instructions to get the cluster up and running. The first part of this guide covers the planning and provisioning of the infrastructure with Proxmox and Terraform. The second part is dedicated to installing Kubernetes and essential software such as Calico for networking, OpenEBS for volume provisioning, and MetalLB for network load balancing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kubeflow Training Operators and Istio: solving the proxy sidecar lifecycle problem for AI/ML workloads</title>
      <link>https://datastrophic.io/kubeflow-training-operators-and-istio-solving-the-proxy-sidecar-lifecycle-problem-for-aiml-workloads/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://datastrophic.io/kubeflow-training-operators-and-istio-solving-the-proxy-sidecar-lifecycle-problem-for-aiml-workloads/</guid>
      <description>With Kubeflow gaining traction in the community and its early adoption in enterprises, security and observability concerns become more and more important. Many organizations that are running AI/ML workloads, operate with sensitive personal or financial data and have stricter requirements for data encryption, traceability, and access control. Quite often, we can see the use of the Istio service mesh for solving these problems and gaining other benefits of the rich functionality it provides.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
