<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spark on datastrophic</title>
    <link>https://datastrophic.io/tags/spark/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spark on datastrophic</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© 2025 datastrophic</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://datastrophic.io/tags/spark/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spark JobServer: from Spark Standalone to Mesos, Marathon and Docker</title>
      <link>https://datastrophic.io/spark-jobserver-from-spark-standalone-to-mesos-marathon-and-docker-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://datastrophic.io/spark-jobserver-from-spark-standalone-to-mesos-marathon-and-docker-part-i/</guid>
      <description>After several years of running Spark JobServer workloads, the need for better availability and multi-tenancy emerged across several projects author was involved in. This blog post covers design decisions made to provide higher availability and fault tolerance of JobServer installations, multi-tenancy for Spark workloads, scalability and failure recovery automation, and software choices made in order to reach these goals. Spark JobServer Spark JobServer is widely used across a variety of reporting and aggregating systems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apache Spark: core concepts, architecture and internals</title>
      <link>https://datastrophic.io/core-concepts-architecture-and-internals-of-apache-spark/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://datastrophic.io/core-concepts-architecture-and-internals-of-apache-spark/</guid>
      <description>This post covers core concepts of Apache Spark such as RDD, DAG, execution workflow, forming stages of tasks, and shuffle implementation and also describes the architecture and main components of Spark Driver. There’s a github.com/datastrophic/spark-workshop project created alongside this post which contains Spark Applications examples and dockerized Hadoop environment to play with. Slides are also available at slideshare. Intro Spark is a generalized framework for distributed data processing providing functional API for manipulating data at scale, in-memory data caching, and reuse across computations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data processing platforms architectures with SMACK: Spark, Mesos, Akka, Cassandra and Kafka</title>
      <link>https://datastrophic.io/data-processing-platforms-architectures-with-spark-mesos-akka-cassandra-and-kafka/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://datastrophic.io/data-processing-platforms-architectures-with-spark-mesos-akka-cassandra-and-kafka/</guid>
      <description>This post is a follow-up of the talk given at Big Data AW meetup in Stockholm and focused on different use cases and design approaches for building scalable data processing platforms with SMACK(Spark, Mesos, Akka, Cassandra, Kafka) stack. While stack is really concise and consists of only several components it is possible to implement different system designs which list not only purely batch or stream processing, but more complex Lambda and Kappa architectures as well.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
